MOHAMED IBRAHIM

ACT & SR. IOS DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME:

T: +20 115 4758745 / +20 102 1927876 E: mohamed.i.elshaer@gmail.com

Linkedin: <u>Linkedin</u> Resume: <u>C.V</u>

CAREER SUMMARY:

An iOS Developer & Co-Instructor with 3 years of experience in iOS Development and 3 years of iOS teaching. who holds an iOS Development Diploma from IDEAcademy and Apple Certified Trainer in mobile applications development in Egypt. has good Leadership, Teamwork, Time management, Communication, and the ability to fast learn. | Good English speaker.

MAIN SKILLS:

- Work With Agile (Jira).
- Works with MVP with Protocols.
- Works With Design Patterns.
- Almofire and Codable.
- Push and Local Notification.
- RESTful API.
- Knowledge MVVM with Rx.
- Knowledge of SOLID Principles.
- Knowledge of VIPER Architecture.
- Familiar with SwiftUI.

EDUCATION:

Faculty of (computers and information). Helwan University, 2020.

Grade: Very Good.

iOS Diploma: IDE Academy, 2017.

T3 (Train The Trainer): LearnQuest 2019.

EXPERIENCE:

GitHub Repo

• The Repo.

ACT | IDEA EG | Sep 2019 - Till Now.

· Woks as ACT (Apple Certified Trainer).

Sr.iOS Developer | Restart Tech | Feb 2023 - Till Now.

- iOS Developer: Working with the Development team for making iOS apps.
- Projects: <u>Banzenty</u>, <u>Yassarnah</u>, <u>Masane3</u>.

iOS Developer | IDEA EG | Aug 2019 - Sep 2022.

- iOS Volger: work with the marking team in order to make learning videos in iOS App Development.
- Co-Instructor: work with the iOS Instructor in education to learn the new students.
- iOS Developer: Working with the Development team for making iOS apps. Projects: IUMAK, ZulaExpress, IDEA Hospital.

iOS Developer | ATW. Ltd | Jun 2018 - Sep 2018.

- Work with UI/UX designer in the team and made these Apps: Zakatona, Salatona.
- Zakatona: The app helps the user to calculate the amount of Zakat on Silver. Gold. etc.
- Salatona: App for prayer time get the location automatically and the Azan for your reign.

iOS Developer | IDEAcademy | Dec 2017 - May 2018.

• Trainee Help new Students in the Academy.

iOS Developer | Freelancer.

• Help the clients in his apps by Fixing app bugs.

SKILLS:

Languages: English (Very Good), Arabic (Fluent).

Technical Skills: Swift with Storyboard, Familiar with SwiftUI, Using Cocoa Pods, good at using Architecture (MVC & MVVM) and Design Patterns, Handling Network Layer.

COURSES:

- Swift 4 & iOS 11, Udemy, 2017.
- Swift 4 & iOS 12 Bootcamp, Udemy, 2018.
- Soft Skills, 57357, 2017, content (Teamwork Communication).